[{"answer": "Well, you know, Elisabeth Kubler-Ross did this thing, this thing called the four stages of death and I actually -- of dying.", "docId": "130917pmt", "aSentId": 38, "question": "How have you been coping?", "qSentId": 37}, {"answer": "You know, I've said almost from the first moment that we learned that, \"We're devastated but we're not destroyed.\"", "docId": "130917pmt", "aSentId": 65, "question": "How have you been coping with this?", "qSentId": 64}, {"answer": "You know, he was -- it was actually one of the best weeks he's had in the long time.", "docId": "130917pmt", "aSentId": 100, "question": "Kay, how had he been the night before?", "qSentId": 99}, {"answer": "He had told me.", "docId": "130917pmt", "aSentId": 141, "question": "And how did you know he had a gun?", "qSentId": 140}, {"answer": "That was late on Thursday, April 4th.", "docId": "130917pmt", "aSentId": 173, "question": "And what time was this?", "qSentId": 172}, {"answer": "I didn't want to see what the possibility was.", "docId": "130917pmt", "aSentId": 231, "question": "Did you go and try and see him?", "qSentId": 230}, {"answer": "Well it -- on a personal level, on a family level, on a government level, there'd be three different answers.", "docId": "130917pmt", "aSentId": 260, "question": "What does that tell you?", "qSentId": 259}, {"answer": "Yes.", "docId": "130917pmt", "aSentId": 274, "question": "In the end, do you believe that he was correctly diagnosed, eventually?", "qSentId": 273}, {"answer": "AY WARREN: Borderline personality disorder.", "docId": "130917pmt", "aSentId": 276, "question": "With something called?", "qSentId": 275}, {"answer": "Well, borderline personality disorder is a -- it's a pervasive attachment, if you will, to mood swings, suicide ideation.", "docId": "130917pmt", "aSentId": 278, "question": "And what is that?", "qSentId": 277}, {"answer": "He had actually made two other attempts that were definite attempts plus all the attempts.", "docId": "130917pmt", "aSentId": 299, "question": "How many times had he actually tried?", "qSentId": 298}, {"answer": "He had overdosed.", "docId": "130917pmt", "aSentId": 306, "question": "Before he'd taken an overdose or something?", "qSentId": 305}, {"answer": "Well, in that situation, I said, \"Matthew, the reason why is there is a purpose, even in our pain.", "docId": "130917pmt", "aSentId": 326, "question": "And what did you say to him, Rick?", "qSentId": 325}, {"answer": "Yeah.", "docId": "130917pmt", "aSentId": 358, "question": "Had he tried to do it legally?", "qSentId": 357}, {"answer": "A month before he took his life.", "docId": "130917pmt", "aSentId": 368, "question": "When did he finally get this gun?", "qSentId": 367}, {"answer": "He told me that he -- he told me everything and he told me that he had found somebody finally on the internet who would sell it to him and it had to be super encrypted and it had to be, you know, this whole process and he begged me to help him because he couldn't figure out the process.", "docId": "130917pmt", "aSentId": 370, "question": "And do you know how he got it, who he got it from?", "qSentId": 369}, {"answer": "Have no idea.", "docId": "130917pmt", "aSentId": 390, "question": "Do you know who that person is, Rick?", "qSentId": 389}, {"answer": "No.", "docId": "130917pmt", "aSentId": 393, "question": "The police have never been able to find out?", "qSentId": 392}, {"answer": "Oh yeah.", "docId": "130917pmt", "aSentId": 398, "question": "And what -- and, Rick, have you been able to forgive this person?", "qSentId": 397}, {"answer": "Yeah.", "docId": "130917pmt", "aSentId": 419, "question": "Is there anything that can be done with that?", "qSentId": 418}, {"answer": "Well yeah.", "docId": "130917pmt", "aSentId": 435, "question": "Is it affecting what you're going to be saying about this going forward?", "qSentId": 434}, {"answer": "It is.", "docId": "130917pmt", "aSentId": 449, "question": "Kay, people say it's a second amendment right of every American to have guns, what do you say to them?", "qSentId": 448}, {"answer": "I was overwhelmed by the love of our people.", "docId": "130917pmt", "aSentId": 482, "question": "Kay you only lasted a couple of minutes, because you found it's so difficult which is completely understandable, but for you Rick that moment when you walked out?", "qSentId": 481}, {"answer": "You know as Rick said it's not -- our faith is currently what's got us -- that foundation what's gotten us through and it's solid and strong but I have to tell you that, you know, before -- I have something I want to show you.", "docId": "130917pmt", "aSentId": 521, "question": "Kay, have you gone through any doubt about your faith?", "qSentId": 520}, {"answer": "Yeah.", "docId": "130917pmt", "aSentId": 558, "question": "Is there any sense of relief as a family that Matthew is now with God in heaven?", "qSentId": 557}, {"answer": "Yeah, if I didn't have that hope I would be in ultimate despair but we have built our lives, our faith, our family, our ministry on the belief that because of Jesus Christ and because of what he did on the cross for us we can have our past forgiven, we have a purpose for living, and we have a home in heaven that takes care of my past, my present, and my future.", "docId": "130917pmt", "aSentId": 560, "question": "Out of pain?", "qSentId": 559}, {"answer": "Yeah.", "docId": "130917pmt", "aSentId": 566, "question": "There have been two strands I think that should be in particularly vicious in your case, one are these fake accounts set up supposedly on your behalf?", "qSentId": 565}, {"answer": "Well, first Matthew wasn't gay but if it was we would have loved him unconditionally anyway.", "docId": "130917pmt", "aSentId": 572, "question": "What is your reaction to it?", "qSentId": 571}, {"answer": "Of course that's part of grief.", "docId": "130917pmt", "aSentId": 583, "question": "Do you have anything you think if only we had tried?", "qSentId": 582}, {"answer": "Rick, the one \"what if\" that springs to mind for me example if I was in your position and thank God I'm not, but if I had been as suppose the what if knowing he'd acquired an illegal gun...", "docId": "130917pmt", "aSentId": 588, "question": "What if we done that?", "qSentId": 587}, {"answer": "No.", "docId": "130917pmt", "aSentId": 596, "question": "... it could have made any difference?", "qSentId": 595}, {"answer": "Exactly.", "docId": "130917pmt", "aSentId": 618, "question": "Does it breaches the family members' right?", "qSentId": 617}, {"answer": "Piers, we've always known since Matthew has lived his entire life that one day we would be spokespeople for mental illness.", "docId": "130917pmt", "aSentId": 630, "question": "Let's get this Rick, have you questioned any stage whether you should have done more as Rick Warren, America's pastor about this issue of mental health before Matthew took his life?", "qSentId": 629}, {"answer": "Oh, my funny, quirky, ridiculously, silly, deeply compassion.", "docId": "130917pmt", "aSentId": 642, "question": "How would you like him to be remembered Kay?", "qSentId": 641}, {"answer": "Well, I know that he's in heaven looking down on us and we have many loved ones there, my parents, Kay's mom and dad and the -- that presence of God is more important than the presence of Matthew in my life.", "docId": "130917pmt", "aSentId": 659, "question": "Do you feel his -- he is here now?", "qSentId": 658}]